[
    {
        "question": "Off the coast of what continent will you find the Strait of Magellan?",
        "answer": "South America"
    },
    {
        "question": "The world-renowned St. Paul`s Cathedral is in what European city?",
        "answer": "London"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the two landlocked countries in South America?",
        "answer": "Bolivia and Paraguay"
    },
    {
        "question": "Although it`s referred to as a `sea`, what body of water is actually the largest lake in the world?",
        "answer": "Caspian Sea"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Solomon Islands?",
        "answer": "Honiara"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what modern-day country did the Sabines live?",
        "answer": "Italy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What city named its airport after Jomo Kenyatta?",
        "answer": "Nairobi"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does the name of the Buddhist temple Angkor Wat mean?",
        "answer": "The name means \u201ctemple city\u201d in the Khmer language, referencing its start as the political center of Emperor Suryavarman."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which French leader commissioned the Arc de Triomphe?",
        "answer": "Napoleon I -- He wanted to both celebrate his military victories and champion public art."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which U.S. landmark was once named Long Acre Square?",
        "answer": "Times Square -- It was once named Long Acre Square after London`s carriage district."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Alcatraz Island named after?",
        "answer": "Birds -- The island was originally named `La Isla de los Alcatraces,` which is Spanish for `The Island of the Pelicans.`"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what Caribbean country did steel drums originate?",
        "answer": "Trinidad and Tobago"
    },
    {
        "question": "What volcanic peak can you see from Naples?",
        "answer": "Mount Vesuvius"
    },
    {
        "question": "What city dug the first subway?",
        "answer": "London"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the Abominable Snowman said to wander?",
        "answer": "The Himalayas"
    },
    {
        "question": "What US city`s skyline boasts the Gateway Arch?",
        "answer": "St. Louis`"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Ethiopia`s main commercial crop?",
        "answer": "Coffee"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Belgian city is one of the world`s main centers for diamond dealing?",
        "answer": "Antwerp"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which city is known as the Windy City?",
        "answer": "Chicago"
    },
    {
        "question": "Belmopan is the capital of which country?",
        "answer": "Belize"
    },
    {
        "question": "Belmopan is the capital of which Central American country?",
        "answer": "Belize"
    },
    {
        "question": "What country is directly west of Spain?",
        "answer": "Portugal"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Botswana?",
        "answer": "Gaborone"
    },
    {
        "question": "What Caribbean island nation`s name comes from the Portuguese word meaning `bearded ones`?",
        "answer": "Barbados"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Yalu River separates China from what other country?",
        "answer": "North Korea"
    },
    {
        "question": "What large island lies about 300 miles due east of Mozambique?",
        "answer": "Madagascar"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which African coast is Somalia located on?",
        "answer": "East"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which ocean does Somalia has water access to?",
        "answer": "Indian"
    },
    {
        "question": "Off what country lies the island of Zanzibar?",
        "answer": "Tanzania"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which ocean is Zanzibar located in?",
        "answer": "Indian"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Cook Islands?",
        "answer": "Avarua"
    },
    {
        "question": "Avarua is the capital of which country?",
        "answer": "Cook Islands"
    },
    {
        "question": "What country is completely enclosed by South Africa?",
        "answer": "Lesotho"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where was the first Broadway theater in New York City?",
        "answer": "Financial District (Broadway`s history began in a 280-person theater on Nassau Street in the Financial District.)"
    },
    {
        "question": "What Caribbean record does the Dominican Republic hold?",
        "answer": "Highest mountain peak - The highest peak in the Caribbean, Pico Duarte, soars 10,417 feet above the trees."
    },
    {
        "question": "What article of the Mexican constitution talks about free education?",
        "answer": "Article 3 of the political constitution of the United Mexican States"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which U.S. state has the peach blossom for its state flower?",
        "answer": "Delaware"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is North Korea`s official name?",
        "answer": "Democratic People`s Republic of Korea (DPRK)"
    },
    {
        "question": "What country\u00b4s national currency is z\u0142oty?",
        "answer": "Poland"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state is home to White Sands National Monument?",
        "answer": "New Mexico"
    },
    {
        "question": "Buffalo Grove is a suburb of what major US city?",
        "answer": "Chicago"
    },
    {
        "question": "After Central Park was completed, New York City`s 4th Avenue, above 32nd Street, was renamed what?",
        "answer": "Park Avenue"
    },
    {
        "question": "What river divides the city of Budapest into the `districts` of Buda and Pest?",
        "answer": "The Danube"
    },
    {
        "question": "What Texas city is nicknamed `The Yellow Rose of Texas`?",
        "answer": "Amarillo"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the better known name of the Spanish mission San Antonio de Valero?",
        "answer": "The Alamo"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the smallest independent country in Asia?",
        "answer": "Maldives"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Island of Bornholm is part of which country?",
        "answer": "Denmark"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Island of Bornholm is part of which European country?",
        "answer": "Denmark"
    },
    {
        "question": "What major river runs through Dublin?",
        "answer": "Liffey"
    },
    {
        "question": "What major river runs through Amsterdam?",
        "answer": "Amstel"
    }
]